const javaInterQuestions = [
  {
    question: "What does polymorphism in Java refer to?",
    option1: "Multiple inheritance",
    option2: "Multiple forms or behaviors",
    option3: " Multiple instances of a class",
    option4: "Multiple data types",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "Which keyword is used to refer to the parent class in Java?",
    option1: "This",
    option2: "Parent",
    option3: "super",
    option4: "extends",

    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the `final` keyword in Java?",
    option1: "Declare a constant",
    option2: "Allow method overriding",
    option3: "Enable dynamic binding",
    option4: "Indicate an abstract class",

    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Which collection type uses a dynamic array in Java?",
    option1: "HashSet",
    option2: "TreeMap",
    option3: "ArrayList",
    option4: "LinkedList",

    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the significance of the `static` keyword in Java?",
    option1: "Define constants",
    option2: "Create dynamic variables",
    option3: "Declare class-level members",
    option4: "Implement inheritance",

    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the `transient` keyword indicate in Java?",
    option1: "Non-accessible",
    option2: "Non-extendable`",
    option3: " Non-serializable",
    option4: "Non-static",

    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: " How is multithreading achieved in Java?",
    option1: "Using the `sync` keyword",
    option2: "Extending the `Runnable` interface",
    option3: " Using the `multithread` class",
    option4: "Implementing the `Singleton` pattern",

    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "What design pattern involves a subject and observers?",
    option1: "Singleton",
    option2: "Adapter",
    option3: " Observer",
    option4: "Decorator",

    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: " Which class is used for mutable string manipulation in Java?",
    option1: "String",
    option2: "StringBuffer",
    option3: "StringBuilder",
    option4: "StringManipulator",

    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the `try-with-resources` statement ensure?",
    option1: "Proper resource management",
    option2: "Exception handling",
    option3: "Synchronization",
    option4: "Code optimization",

    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Which keyword is used for method overloading in Java?",
    option1: "override",
    option2: "overloading",
    option3: "overloaded",
    option4: "None of the above",

    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the `Enum` class represent in Java?",
    option1: "Enumeration of integers",
    option2: "Singleton instances",
    option3: "Fixed set of constants`",
    option4: "Enumerated arrays",

    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the `hashCode()` method in Java?",
    option1: "Compare objects",
    option2: "Provide a unique identifier",
    option3: "Calculate hash values",
    option4: "Access object fields",

    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "How is anonymous class different from a regular class?",
    option1: "It cannot implement interfaces",
    option2: "It has a name",
    option3: "It is unnamed and created for a specific purpose",
    option4: "It cannot extend other classes",

    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the `assert` statement in Java?",
    option1: "Error handling",
    option2: "Code optimization",
    option3: "Debugging and testing",
    option4: "Exception throwing",

    ans: 3,
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which operator is used to test if an object is an instance of a particular class or interface?*",
    option1: "instanceof",
    option2: "isInstance",
    option3: "typeOf",
    option4: "isInstanceOf",

    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "How does the `Comparable` interface differ from the `Comparator` interface?",
    option1:
      "Comparable is for natural ordering, Comparator for custom ordering",
    option2:
      "Comparator is for natural ordering, Comparable for custom ordering",
    option3: "Both are used for natural ordering",
    option4: "Neither are used for ordering",

    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the diamond operator (`&lt;&gt;`) simplify in Java?",
    option1: "Type casting",
    option2: "Generics syntax",
    option3: "Exception handling",
    option4: "Method overloading",

    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "What does reflection in Java enable?",
    option1: "Compile-time error checking",
    option2: "Dynamic class loading and method invocation",
    option3: "Type casting",
    option4: "Garbage collection",

    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which keyword is used to refer to the current instance of the class?",
    option1: "this",
    option2: "self",
    option3: "current",
    option4: "instance",

    ans: 1,
  },
];

export default javaInterQuestions;
